(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.2",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-pro-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da Da-da-da-da-da
誰が袖に咲く幻花
A phantom flower blooming on one's sleeve
ただそこに愛を落とした
I simply dropped love right there
派手に色を溶かすように
As if flamboyantly melting the colors
銀朱の月を添えて
With the vermilion moon accompanying it
転がるように風を切って
Cutting through the wind as if tumbling
躓くごとに強くなった
Becoming stronger with every stumble
光も痛みも怒りも全部
Light, pain, and anger, all of it
抱きしめて
Embrace them tight
選ばれなければ
If you aren't chosen
選べばいい
Then just choose
声よ 轟け
Roar, oh voice!
夜のその向こうへ
Towards the other side of the night
涙で滲んでた
That was blurred by tears
あんなに遠くの景色まで
Reaching even that scenery so far away
響き渡れ
Resound far and wide
何を奏でて
What are you playing?
誰に届けたくて
Who do you want to reach?
不確かなままでいい
It's fine to remain uncertain
どんなに暗い感情も
No matter how dark the emotions
どんなに長い葛藤も
No matter how long the struggle
歌と散れ
Scatter with the song
残響
Reverberation
Da-da-da-da-da-da-da-da Da-da-da-da-da
ただ一人舞う千夜
Just dancing alone for a thousand nights
結えない帯を結べば
If I tie the sash that cannot be tied
派手な色も負かすように
As if to outshine even the flashy colors
深紅の香こそあわれ
The crimson scent is truly moving
この先どんなつらい時も
No matter how painful the times ahead
口先よりも胸を張って
Stand proud rather than just talking
抱いた夢の明かりを全部
All the light of the dreams I embraced
辿るだけ
I'll just follow them
逃げ出すため
To run away...
ここまで来た
...is not the reason I came this far
んじゃないだろ
Is it now?
選ばれなければ 選べばいい
If you aren't chosen, you just have to choose.
声を枯らして 燃える花のように
With a hoarse voice, like a burning flower,
闇を纏って 照らしたら
if I clad myself in darkness and shine,
曖昧すぎる世界も 譜面にして
I'll turn even this too-ambiguous world into a score.
夜を数えて 朝を描くような
Counting the nights, like sketching the morning,
鮮やかな音を鳴らす
I'll play a vivid sound.
どんなに深い後悔も
No matter how deep the regret,
どんなに高い限界も
no matter how high the limit,
掻き消して 残響
drown it out, reverberation.
はーい！ということで ホロアコースティックライブ in Summer
Okay! So, Holo Acoustic Live in Summer...
始まりましたー！
...has started!
イェーイ！
Yay!
始まったよー！
It's started!
はい ということで お越しくださってる皆様 ありがとうございます！
Yes, so, to everyone who has come to watch, thank you so much!
それでは最初に 今日はいろんな 一緒に歌っていただくメンバーがいっぱいいるんですけども
First off, we have many members singing with us today,
自己紹介をそれぞれさせていただきたいと思います
so I'd like us to introduce ourselves.
まずはホロライブ6期生 秘密結社holoXの頭脳！
First, Hololive 6th Gen, Secret Society holoX's Brain!
博衣こよりだよー！ よろしくお願いしまーす！
It's Hakui Koyori! Nice to meet you!
ずのー！ ずのー！
Brain! Brain!
はい そして一曲目から来ていただいたのは まずミオ先輩！
Yes! And joining me for the first song, first is Mio-senpai!
うちうち！ うちだよ！
It's me, it's me! It's me!
大神ミオだよー！
It's Ookami Mio!
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオでーす！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
大神ミオだよー！
It's Ookami Mio!
そしてー！
And then!
あ、あたし！？
Oh, me!?
ちゃんと自己紹介しないと！
Gotta introduce myself properly!
みなさーん 森カリオペです Hololive Englishの死神ですです
Everyone! I'm Mori Calliope. Hololive English's Reaper.
よろしくお願いしまーす！ 楽しもう！
Nice to meet you! Let's have fun!
Let's have fun everyone!
今日ね お忙しい中 アコースティックライブ出演していただきありがとうございます
Thank you for appearing in this acoustic live today despite being busy.
いやこちらこそ 呼んでいただきありがとうございます
No, thank you for inviting us.
そしてですね 今回はなんと ピアノも生演奏でお届けさせていただきます
And also! This time, we are bringing you a live piano performance as well.
こよりの生誕ライブでも演奏していただきました
She also played at Koyori's birthday live.
ウイングさんでーす！
It's Wings-san!
わあ 素敵ですね
Wow, lovely.
美しい
Beautiful.
はい このライブはですね 最初から最後まで 完全生放送
Yes, so this live is a completely live broadcast from start to finish.
そして生演奏でお届けさせていただきますので
And since we are bringing it to you with live music,
えー よしなによろしくお願いいたします
please treat us kindly.
ま なんでこのライブをやる事になったかと言いますとですね
Well, if you ask why we decided to do this live...
ま 普通のライブ そういう生誕ライブとか周年ライブとかって
Usually, for lives like birthday or anniversary concerts,
このダンスレッスン頑張ったりとか
we work hard on dance lessons,
ゲストパートはね 収録でやったりとか
do guest parts via pre-recording,
あの 後ろのモニター作ったりとか
or create the background monitor visuals.
ま とにかく準備が大変なんですよね
Anyway, the preparation is really tough.
一つ作るのにね すごく時間がかかるんですけど
It takes a lot of time to make just one,
アコースティックライブだったら
but if it's an acoustic live,
もう集まって 演奏していただいて
we just gather, have them play,
歌ったら当日でいけるんじゃね？というのを
sing, and couldn't we just pull it off on the day?
ちょっとチャレンジしてみた という形になっております
That's the challenge we decided to try this time.
まあでもね 歌っていただくので 皆さんには大変なんですけども
But well, since you have to sing, it's tough for everyone anyway.
いや 楽しかったよね
No, it was fun!
楽しかった！ 嬉しい！
It was fun! I'm happy!
お揃いみたいな感じだね
It feels like we're matching.
でも何か真ん中にこよが入ることで 何かいい感じにまとまってるね
But with Koyo in the middle, it somehow comes together nicely.
そう このカラーリング的にね この並びになりました
Yes, we ended up in this order because of the coloring.
もしかしたら今ね ちょっとあの コメントが止まっちゃってるかもしれないんですけども
Actually, right now, the comments might have stopped working,
また動き出すと思うので 皆さんちょっと様子見つつ
but I think they'll start moving again, so please keep an eye out.
あとトレンド今3位までいってるということで
Also, we're currently trending at #3!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
序盤なのに！
Even though it's just the beginning!
そんな感じでね ハッシュタグ こちら #holoAcousticLive
So please, use the hashtag here: #holoAcousticLive.
スクショも感想も全部見ますので ぜひツイートしてください
I'll look at all your screenshots and impressions, so please tweet them!
さて一曲目は『残響散歌』でしたけれども ミオ先輩どうでしたか？
So, the first song was 'Zankyou Sanka', but how was it, Mio-senpai?
えっと すごい あの こうやって一緒に歌うのめっちゃ楽しいよね
Um, well, it's really... singing together like this is so much fun.
で 何かこう かっこいい感じの歌を
And, singing a cool song like this...
こうやって歌うの すごい楽しかったなーって
...in this way was really fun.
めっちゃ頑張っててすごい上手くなってたからさ
You worked so hard and got so good!
嬉しいけどすごい緊張しちゃった一曲目だから
I'm happy, but I was so nervous since it was the first song.
ちょっと一緒に歌っててすごいテンション上がりました。
Singing together really got my hype up!
ありがとうございました。
Thank you so much.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you!
Calli先輩どうですか？
Calli-senpai, how was it?
かっこいい曲大好きです。
I love cool songs.
実はあのこの曲あんまり知らなかったから
Actually, I didn't know this song very well...
歌ったことなかったから何回も練習して
...and I'd never sung it before, so I practiced it many times.
少しずつ上手くなってきたかもしれないけど頑張りました。
I might have gotten better bit by bit, but I did my best.
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
元々知ってると勝手に思うぐらい上手だったよね。
You were so good I assumed you already knew it!
完璧でした！
It was perfect!
こより的には今日は夏っぽい曲を揃えて
For me, I wanted to put together a setlist of summer-ish songs today.
夏の曲ってエモい曲が多くて
Summer songs tend to be emotional...
一発目はやっぱりかっこよくバーンって盛り上げて始めたいなと思ったので
...but I wanted to start with a bang and get hyped with something cool for the first one!
かっこいい二人に挟まれてこれ大丈夫かなみたいな感じだったんですけど
Being sandwiched between two cool people, I was like 'Am I gonna be okay?'
一緒に歌えてめちゃくちゃ楽しかった！
But singing together was so much fun!
それではそろそろ次の曲に行くメンバーをお呼びしたいと思いますよ。
Alright then, I'd like to call out the member for the next song.
Biboo!
Bon-Bijou! Hololive English Adventの輝く宝石、古石ビジューだよ！
Bon-Bijou! Hololive English Advent's Shining Jewel, Koseki Bijou!
キラキラ～宝石～
Sparkling~ Jewel~
Thank you for coming today!
かわいい！ちっちゃい！
So cute! So small!
このあとBijou、Singing、どう？
After this, Bijou, Singing, how is it?
ちょっと緊張...
A little nervous...
このあとは2曲続けてお届けさせていただくんですけども
We'll be bringing you two songs in a row after this.
次の曲はCalli先輩とBibooの二人で
The next song will be Calli-senpai and Biboo together.
Yeah! Represent! Represent!
どんな曲なのか... Rock?
What kind of song is it... Rock?
Rock'n Roll! Rock'n Roll!
二人の声にめちゃくちゃ合う曲を選んでますので
We chose a song that fits your voices perfectly...
堪能していただきたいなと思います。
...so I hope everyone enjoys it.
我々は一緒に客席いきましょう。
We'll go down to the audience seats together.
ゆっくり休んでください！
Please rest up!
頑張ってね！
Good luck!
Just you and me now.
English time? 大丈夫ですか？
English time? Are you okay?
楽しもう！
Let's have fun!
We're rock and rolling!
Please listen everyone to...
風といっしょに
Kaze to Issho ni (Together with the Wind).
歩き続けて どこまでゆくの
Walking on and on, how far will I go?
風に尋ねられて 立ち止まる
Asked by the wind, I stop and stand still.
ひとつめの太鼓 トクンと鳴って
The first drum beats, with a 'thump'.
風といっしょに
With the Wind
いのち始まった
Life began
やがて何かを求めて
Eventually seeking something
小さな手のひらを広げ
Opening small palms
キミはすぐに見つけたね
You found it right away, didn't you?
キミじゃない誰かを
Someone who isn't you
誕生日祝う
Celebrating a birthday
ろうそく増えたけど
Though the candles increased
ただ一つの
The one and only
ふるさと旅立った
Left the hometown
今も何かを求めて
Still seeking something even now
大きな瞳輝いて
With big eyes shining
キミのポケットの中には
Inside your pocket
キミじゃない誰かとの
With someone who isn't you
いくつもの出会い
Many encounters
いくつもの別れ
Many partings
まぼろしのような思い出も
Even memories like illusions
少し
A little
歩き続けてどこまで行くの
Walking on, how far will you go?
風に尋ねられて空を見る
Asked by the wind, looking at the sky
歩き続けてどこまで行こうか
Walking on, how far shall we go?
風といっしょにまた歩き出そう
Let's start walking again together with the wind
大地踏みしめどこまでも行こう
Treading the earth, let's go anywhere
目指したあの夢を掴むまで
Until we grasp that dream we aimed for
大地踏みしめどこまでも行こう
Treading the earth, let's go anywhere
目指したあの夢を掴むまで
Until we grasp that dream we aimed for
La la la...
花に亡霊
Ghost in a Flower
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
While sitting in the summer shade
アイスを口に放り込んで
Tossing a popsicle into my mouth
風を待っていた
I was waiting for the wind
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
世の中の全部嘘だらけ
The whole world is full of lies
本当の価値を二人で
True value, the two of us
探しに行こうと笑ったこと
Laughed about going to find it
忘れないように
So I won't forget
色褪せないように
So it won't fade
形に残るものが
That things that remain in form
全てじゃないように
Aren't everything
言葉をもっと教えて
Teach me more words
夏が来るって教えて
Tell me that summer is coming
僕は描いてる
I am sketching
目に映ったのは夏の亡霊だ
What was reflected in my eyes was a summer ghost
思い出なんて忘れて
Forget about memories,
浅い呼吸をする
And take shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping the sweat, it begins to feel like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
夏の木陰に座った頃を
The time we sat in the summer shade.
遠くの丘から顔出した
Remember the cloud that peeked out
雲があったじゃないか
from the distant hill?
君はそれを掴もうとして
You tried to grab it,
馬鹿みたいに空を切った手で
Your hand cutting through the air like a fool.
僕は紙切れもう一を書いて
I drew on a scrap of paper,
笑って握って見せて
Laughed, crumpled it, and showed it to you.
忘れないように
So I wouldn't forget,
色褪せないように
So it wouldn't fade away.
歴史に残るものが
Because things recorded in history
全てじゃないから
Aren't everything.
今だけ顔を失くして
Losing my face just for now,
言葉を全部忘れて
Forgetting all words.
君は笑ってる
You are laughing.
夏を待っている僕ら亡霊だ
We, waiting for summer, are ghosts.
心をもっと教えて
Tell me more about your heart,
夏の匂いを教えて
Tell me the smell of summer.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
忘れないように
So I wouldn't forget,
色褪せないように
So it wouldn't fade away.
心に響くものが
Because things that resonate in the heart
全てじゃないから
Aren't everything.
言葉をもっと教えて
Tell me more words,
さよならだって教えて
Tell me it's goodbye.
今も見るんだよ
I still see it now,
夏に咲いている花に亡霊を
The ghost in the flower blooming in summer.
言葉じゃなくて時間を
Not words, but time.
時間じゃなくて心を
Not time, but the heart.
浅い呼吸をする
Taking shallow breaths.
汗を拭って夏めく
Wiping the sweat, it becomes summer-like.
夏の匂いがする
It smells like summer.
もう忘れてしまったかな
Have you forgotten already?
夏の木陰に座ったまま
While sitting in the summer shade.
アイスを口に放り込んで
Threw ice cream into my mouth,
風を待っていた
And waited for the wind.
はい！ ということで『花に亡霊』でした！
Yes! So, that was 'Hana ni Borei'!
AZKi先輩、ようこそ！
AZKi-senpai, welcome!
お邪魔します！
Thanks for having me!
みんな、こんこんこんこん、こあずき！
Everyone, Kon-kon-kon-kon, Ko-AZKi!
右手にマイク、左手に地図
Mic in the right hand, map in the left hand.
あなたのハートをゼロゲッサー！
I'll Zero-Guesser your heart!
ということで、AZKiです！
So, this is AZKi!
ようこそです！
Welcome!
わあ、すごい素敵なライブにご招待いただきありがとうございます！
Wow, thank you so much for inviting me to such a wonderful concert!
こちらこそご出演いただきありがとうございます！
Thank you for appearing!
ああ、嬉しい！
Ah, I'm so happy!
嬉しい！
So happy!
この曲はですね、あのAZKi先輩にちょっと歌いたい曲...
This song, um, for songs I wanted to sing with AZKi-senpai...
アンケートみたいなのをすごい前に...
...I sent a questionnaire quite a while ago.
そうですね、アンケートありましたね。
That's right, there was a questionnaire.
そちらで「こよりと一緒に歌いたい曲」のところに書いてくださっていた楽曲でした。
It was a song you listed under 'Songs I want to sing with Koyori'.
やっぱり「夏」って聞いて、この曲は外せないなと思いまして。
When I heard 'summer', I thought I couldn't leave this song out.
そうですね！ しかも、あのアコースティックにめちゃくちゃ合う！
That's true! Plus, it fits the acoustic style so well!
めちゃくちゃ合う！
It fits so well!
まああのコメント欄でもあったんですけど...
Well, it was mentioned in the comments too...
あの「これAZKiちのオハコやん」みたいな。
Like, 'Isn't this AZKi-chi's specialty?'
え、でもこよちゃんも歌ってるの見かけてて。
Eh, but I saw Koyo-chan singing it too.
全く、こよもよく歌う。
Totally, Koyo sings it often too.
だからもうあの、せっかくだから。
So, since we have the chance.
やっぱこの夏の終わりに歌いたいなと思って選びました。
I chose it because I wanted to sing it at the end of this summer.
ねえ、めっちゃ浄化されました、横で歌ってて。
Right. I was totally purified singing next to you.
え、こよちゃんどうでしたか？
Eh, how was it, Koyo-chan?
いや、本当によかったし...
No, it was really good and...
え、どうですか？ なんかオハコだけど、このアコースティックとかで歌ったことってございます？
So, it is your specialty, but have you ever sung it acoustically like this?
あ、でもあんまりないかも。
Ah, actually, maybe not much.
おおー！
Ooh!
いやしかもね、こよちゃんと一緒に歌うことで。
Plus, by singing with Koyo-chan...
なんかこう... え、「あずこよ」ある？
It's like... eh, is there 'Azu-Koyo'?
「あずこよ」ある？
Is there 'Azu-Koyo'?
「あずこよ」ある！
There is 'Azu-Koyo'!
「あずこよあるぞ」というね、コメントをちらほら見かけましたので。
I saw comments saying 'Azu-Koyo exists' here and there.
ね、見ました見ました、嬉しい！
Right, I saw them too! I'm happy!
嬉しい！
Happy!
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
ちょっとね、このAZKi先輩の透き通ってる声を、お邪魔しないようにも頑張って透き通らせました。
I tried my best to make my voice transparent so I wouldn't disturb AZKi-senpai's clear voice.
Xトレンド1位！
We're #1 on X trending!
イェーイ！嬉しい！
Yay! I'm so happy!
わあ、みんなありがとう！
Wow, thank you everyone!
もっともっと呟いちゃってください！
Please keep posting more and more!
嬉しい！ありがとう！
I'm happy! Thank you!
それではですね、ちょっと語りたいこともあるんですけれども
Well then, there's more I'd love to talk about, but...
そろそろ次の曲に行きたいと思うのですが
...it's about time to move on to the next song.
次のメンバーをまず呼び込みたいと思いますよ！
First, I'd like to bring out the next members!
ミオ先輩と、ビブー！
Mio-senpai and Biboo!
ミオちゃん、ビブー！
Mio-chan, Biboo!
イェーイイェーイ！おお、元気元気？
Yay yay! Oh, feeling energetic?
元気あり余ってる？
Overflowing with energy?
なんかすごい... さっきまでちょっとエモくてしっとりみたいな...
It was amazing... up until now it was kinda emotional and mellow...
ね、なんかしっとりしたね。
Right, it was quite mellow.
あれあれ？袖からだったから？
Huh? Was it because we were watching from the wings?
二人は元気してたんですね。
You two were full of energy, huh.
はい！えらいです！
Yes! Good job!
えらい？えらい？
Good job? Good job?
あ、エモい！エモい！
Ah, Emotional! Emotional!
エモい。えらい。
Emotional. Great.
エモスティック？ん？エモティック？エモーショナル？
Emostic? Hmm? Emotic? Emotional?
エモーショナル！
Emotional!
エモーショナルにお届けしております。
We're bringing you an emotional performance.
ではですね、ここでちょっとAZKi先輩お着替えに...
Well then, AZKi-senpai is going to go change now...
ちょっと着替えてきます！
I'll go get changed!
いってらっしゃい！お願いします！
See you soon! Go ahead!
でもエモーショナルと言えば、ね、ロックンロールかと思っていた
But speaking of emotional, right, I thought it would be Rock'n'Roll...
カリ先輩とビブーの『風と一緒に』もめっちゃ良かったですよ！
...but Calli-senpai and Biboo's 'Wind' performance was amazing too!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
なんかね、あの皆『え？ロックじゃないの？』みたいな...
Yeah, everyone seemed like, 'Eh? It's not rock?'...
戸惑ってるのも...
Even their confusion was...
ロックじゃないよ。
It wasn't rock, you know.
あ、おかえり！
Ah, welcome back!
早い！
That was fast!
お着替え早い！
You changed so fast!
はい、というわけで、夏はねエモい曲が多い感じですけど
Yes, so, it feels like summer has a lot of emotional songs, but...
次からはどうなるのか...
I wonder what's coming next...
ここからは、3曲続けてお届けいたします。
From here, we'll bring you three songs in a row.
次の曲はですね、こちらのAZKi先輩、ミオ先輩、ビブーちゃんの3人に歌っていただきますので
For the next song, AZKi-senpai, Mio-senpai, and Biboo-chan will be singing for us.
わー！頑張るぞ！
Waaa! I'll do my best!
こよりはしばらくバイバイでーす。
Koyori is saying bye-bye for a while.
いってらっしゃい！頑張ってくるね！
See you later! Good luck!
で、ここで一発やっぱロックンロール...
So, right here, as expected, a blast of Rock'n'Roll...
え？ロックンロール？
Eh? Rock'n'Roll?
嘘！台本にないこと... 戸惑ってる...
Just kidding! Saying things not in the script... you look confused...
はい、というわけでね、まあここから3曲続くんですが、じゃこの3人で歌わせていただきます。
Yes, so anyway, three songs are coming up, and the three of us will be singing.
それでは聴いてください。
Please listen.
スパークル。
Sparkle.
まだこの世界は
This world still seems like...
僕を飼いならしてたいみたいだ
...it wants to keep me tamed.
望み通りだろう？
Isn't that just what you wanted?
美しくもがくよ
I will struggle beautifully.
互いの砂時計
Let's gaze at each other's hourglasses...
眺めながらキスをしようよ
...and share a kiss.
「さよなら」から一番遠い
Let's meet at the place...
場所で待ち合わせよう
...farthest away from "Goodbye".
ついに時は来た
The time has finally come.
昨日までは序章の序章で
Until yesterday was just the prologue of the prologue.
飛ばし読みでいいから
You can just skim through it.
ここからが僕だよ
From here on, it's me.
経験と知識と
With experience and knowledge...
カビの生えかかった勇気を持って
...and a bit of moldy courage...
未だかつてないスピードで
...at an unprecedented speed...
君の元へダイブを
...I'll dive to where you are.
まどろみの中で 生温いコーラに
In a slumber, with lukewarm cola...
ここでないどこかを 夢見たよ
...I dreamed of a place that isn't here.
教室の窓の外に
Outside the classroom window...
電車に揺られ運ばれる朝に
...in the morning carried by the swaying train.
運命だとか未来とか
Words like "destiny" or "future"...
って言葉がどれだけ手を
...no matter how much they extend their hands...
伸ばそうと届かない
...they can't reach the place...
場所で僕ら恋をする
...where we fall in love.
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock too...
横目に見ながら進む
...glance sideways at us as they move on.
こんな世界を二人で
In a world like this, the two of us...
一生 いや、何章でも
...let's survive a lifetime, no, many chapters...
生き抜いていこう
...and go on living together.
スパークル (original ver.)
Sparkle (original ver.)
遥か彼方へと追いやって
Driving it far away into the distance
千年周期を
The thousand-year cycle
一日で息しよう
Let's live it in a single day
辞書にある言葉で
With words found in the dictionary
出来上がった世界を憎んだ
I hated the world that was made
万華鏡の中で
Inside a kaleidoscope
八月のある朝
One morning in August
君は僕の前で
You were in front of me
ハニかんでは澄ましてみせた
Acting shy, then composing yourself
この世界の教科書
A textbook of this world
のような笑顔で
With a smile like that
嘘みたいな日々を 規格外の意味を
Days like lies, meanings outside the norm
悲劇だっていいから望んだよ
I wished for it, even if it was a tragedy
そしたらドアの外に
And then, outside the door
君が全部抱えて立ってたよ
You were standing there holding everything
運命だとか未来とか
Fate and the future and such
って言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how much those words
伸ばそうと届かない
Reach out their hands, they can't reach
場所で
In a place
僕ら
We
遊ぼうか
Shall we play?
愛し方さえも
Even the way to love
君の匂いがした
Smelled like you
歩き方さえも
Even the way of walking
その笑い声がした
Had the sound of that laughter
いつか消えてなくなる
Someday it will disappear and be gone
君のすべてを
Everything about you
この目に焼き付けて
Burning it into these eyes
おくことはもう権利なんかじゃない
Is no longer a right
義務だと思うんだ
I think it's a duty
運命だとか未来とか
Fate and the future and such
って言葉がどれだけ手を
No matter how much those words
伸ばそうと届かない
Reach out their hands, they can't reach
場所で僕ら恋をする
In a place where we fall in love
時計の針も二人を
The hands of the clock also
横目に見ながら進む
Move forward while glancing at the two of us
そんな世界を二人で
In such a world, together
一生 いや、何章でも
For a lifetime, no, for however many chapters
生き抜いて
Surviving through
行こう
Let's go
ガーネット / 作詞・作曲：奥 華子
Garnet / Lyrics & Music: Hanako Oku
グラウンド駆けてく
Running across the ground
あなたの背中は
Your back
空に浮かんだ
Floating in the sky
雲よりも自由で
More free than the clouds
ノートに並んだ
Lined up in the notebook
四角い文字さえ
Even the square letters
すべてを照らす
Illuminating everything
好きという気持ちがわからなくて
I didn't understand what it meant to love someone.
二度とは戻らないこの時間が
But this time that will never return...
その意味をあたしに教えてくれた
...taught me the meaning of it all.
あなたと過ごした日々を この胸に焼き付けよう
I'll burn the days I spent with you into my heart.
思い出さなくても大丈夫なように
So that I'll be okay, even if I don't actively remember them.
いつか他の誰かを好きになったとしても
Even if someday I fall in love with someone else...
あなたは ずっと 特別で
You will always be special.
大切で またこの季節が
You're precious to me. And as this season...
めぐってく
...comes around again.
皆さん お待たせしました！
Everyone, sorry to keep you waiting!
ちょっと生ならではという感じで
In a true 'live broadcast' fashion...
原因不明の機材トラブルが起きてしまいまして
we experienced some equipment trouble of unknown cause.
今のところ あの 原因もわかってないんですけども
Right now, um, we don't even know what caused it, but...
Wow. Wow.
Our singing so good it broke the stream!
お待たせしました 復旧したので
Sorry for the wait. We've recovered now, so...
…歌おうと思います。
...I think we'll sing.
皆さんお待たせしてごめんね。
Sorry for keeping you waiting, everyone.
なんかちょっとビリビリってなったみたいで耳とかも
It seems there was some buzzing, even in your ears.
調子合わせながら
While we adjust things,
このアコースティックライブで耳治していただければと思います。
I hope you can soothe your ears with this acoustic live.
はい。
Yes.
では、ヴィンさんもありがとうございます。
And Vin-san, thank you too.
添えていただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for the accompaniment.
では、行きますか。
Shall we go?
はい。
Yes.
OK？
Okay?
OK。
Okay.
OK！
Okay!
グラウンド駆けてく
Running across the ground,
あなたの背中は
your back
空に浮かんだ
floating in the sky,
雲よりも自由で
was freer than the clouds.
ノートに並んだ
Even the square letters
四角い文字さえ
lined up in my notebook
すべてを照らす
looked like a light
光に見えた
illuminating everything.
好きという気持ちが
I didn't understand
分からなくて
the feeling of "love".
二度とは戻らない
This time that
この時間が
will never return,
その意味をわたしに
you taught me
教えてくれた
the meaning of it.
あなたと過ごした日々を
I'll burn the days I spent with you
この胸に焼き付けよう
into my heart,
思い出さなくても
so that I'll be okay
大丈夫なように
even if I don't recall them.
いつか他の誰かを
Even if I fall in love
好きになったとしても
with someone else someday,
あなたはずっと特別で
you will always be special,
大切で
and precious.
またこの季節がめぐってくる
This season will come around again.
初めて二人で
After school, when we talked
話した放課後
together for the first time,
誰も知らない
I was looking for a smile
笑顔探していた
no one else knew.
遠くであなたの
At your voice
はしゃいでる声に
frolicking in the distance,
なぜだか胸が
for some reason,
痛くなったの
my chest started to ache.
変わってゆくことを
I was afraid
怖がってたの
of things changing.
ずっと友達の
I felt like we could stay
ままいれる気がした
friends forever.
終わってくものなど
I thought nothing
ないと思った
would ever end.
果てしない時の中で
In the endless flow of time,
あなたと出会えたことが
that I was able to meet you,
何よりも私を強くしてくれたね
made me stronger than anything else.
夢中でかける明日に
Even if I reach the tomorrow
辿り着いたとしても
I'm running frantically toward,
あなたはずっと特別で
you will always be special,
大切で
and precious.
またこの季節がやってくる
This season will come again.
いつまでも
That I'd never
忘れないと
forget,
あなたが言って
the summer
くれた夏
you told me that.
時が流れ
Time flows,
今頃私は
and by now I...
涙がこぼれてきた
Tears spilled over.
あなたと過ごした日々を
I'll burn the days I spent with you
この胸に焼き付けよう
into my heart,
思い出さなくても
so that I'll be okay
大丈夫なように
even if I don't recall them.
好きになったとしても
Even if I fell in love
あなたは
You will
ずっと
Always
特別で
Be special
大切で
And precious to me
またこの季節が
This season will again
めぐってくる
Come around
打上花火
Fireworks
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out at that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, and the sight of your back
寄り返す波が足元をよぎり何かをさらう
The waves rushing back cross our feet and carry something away
夕凪の中 日暮れだけが通り過ぎて行く
In the evening calm, only the twilight passes by
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks that suddenly flashed and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
Surely, the summer that hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted and connected our ambiguous hearts
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
あと何度君と同じ花火を見られるかなって
Thinking about how many more times I can watch the same fireworks with you
笑う顔に何ができるだろうか
I wonder what I can do for your smiling face
傷つくこと 喜ぶこと 繰り返す波と情動
Getting hurt, feeling joy, the repeating waves and emotions
焦燥 最終列車の音
Impatience, the sound of the last train
何度でも言葉にして君を呼ぶよ
I'll put it into words and call out to you again and again
波間を選び もう一度
Choosing between the waves, once more
もう二度と悲しまずに
So that we won't be sad ever again
住むように
As if living there
ハッと息を飲めば 消えちゃいそうな光が
If I held my breath in surprise, the light looked like it would vanish
きっとまだ 胸に住んでいた
Surely, it was still living in my heart
手を伸ばせば触れた あったかい未来は
The warm future I touched when I reached out my hand
ひそかに二人を見ていた
Was secretly watching the two of us
パッと花火が
The fireworks suddenly
夜に咲いた
Bloomed in the night
夜に咲いて
Blooming in the night
静かに消えた
Quietly faded away
離さないで
Don't let go
もう少しだけ
Just a little longer
もう少しだけ このままで
Just a little longer, just like this
あの日見渡した渚を 今も思い出すんだ
I still remember the shore we looked out at that day
砂の上に刻んだ言葉 君の後ろ姿
The words carved in the sand, and the sight of your back
パッと光って咲いた 花火を見ていた
We watched the fireworks that suddenly flashed and bloomed
きっとまだ 終わらない夏が
Surely, the summer that hasn't ended yet
曖昧な心を 解かして繋いだ
Melted and connected our ambiguous hearts
この夜が 続いて欲しかった
I wanted this night to go on forever
Da la la la la la...
はい、ということで、カリオペちゃんと『打上花火』を歌わせていただきました！
Okay, so, I had the pleasure of singing 'Uchiage Hanabi' with Calliope-chan!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
花火きれいでした。
The fireworks were beautiful.
ワー、楽しかった！
Wow, that was fun!
どうでしたか？
How was it?
ワー、とっても楽しかったけど。
Wow, it was really fun, though.
嬉しい。カリオペちゃんとこうやってね、デュエットできる日が来るとは...
I'm happy. To think the day would come when I could duet with Calliope-chan like this...
思わず、もう本当に...
I never expected it, really...
イェーイ、私... 頑張りました低い声で。
Yay, I... did my best with a low voice.
分かった、分かった！めっちゃかっこよかった！
I know, I know! It was so cool!
ありがとう。もうコントラストがすごい好きだから、そう、低い声でやりたいなと思って。
Thanks. I really like the contrast, so yeah, I wanted to do it with a low voice.
すごいね、男性パートをね、頑張って歌ってくださいました。カリオペちゃんありがとう。
It's amazing, you worked hard singing the male part. Thank you, Calliope-chan.
こちらこそありがとうございます。楽しかった。
Thank you too. It was fun.
楽しかった！ということで...
It was fun! So...
ここでね、また、じゃメンバーのみんなを、え、呼びたいと思います。
Here, again, well, I'd like to call everyone, the members.
全員集合！
Everyone assemble!
Come on!
イェーイ！Come on! イェイイェイイェイ！
Yeaah! Come on! Yay yay yay!
はーい、最高だった。
Yes, it was the best.
よかったね。
It was good, huh.
ずっと最高です。
It's always the best.
素敵でした本当に。
It was really wonderful.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
ということですね、改めまして、本日はアコースティックライブ、え、出演いただき、そして見ていただき、ありがとうございます！
So, once again, thank you for appearing in and watching today's Acoustic Live!
ありがとう！ Thank you so much!
Thank you! Thank you so much!
もう本当に、ま選曲神だったなって自分で思うぐらいね、みんなの歌声が...
Really, the song selection was god-tier, I think to myself, everyone's singing voices were...
自画自賛。
Self-praise.
自画自賛するぐらいみんなが本当に素晴らしくて幸せなひとときを過ごさせていただきました。ありがとうございます。
Self-praise aside, everyone was truly wonderful and I had a happy time. Thank you.
ありがとうございました！素敵な時間よ。
Thank you very much! It was a wonderful time.
というわけですね、なんと次が、最後の曲になってしまいました！
So, surprisingly, the next song will be the last one!
ええええ！？今来たばっかり！
Eeeeeh!? We just got here!
今来たばっかりだよ...
We just got here...
ラストはね、この全員揃って歌いますので、え、お楽しみにしていただけると嬉しいんですが...
For the last one, we will all sing together, so I hope you look forward to it, but...
ラストに行く前に、ちょっとせっかくなんで、ピアノの前でスクショタイムとかしましょうか？
Before the last one, since we're here, shall we have a screenshot time in front of the piano?
Oh! いいね！思い出思い出。
Oh! Nice! Memories, memories.
皆さんも撮ってください。
Everyone please take photos too.
じゃあ今日はしゃがむね。
Then today I'll crouch.
イェーイ！
Yeah!
いい写真。
Nice photo.
皆さん撮れました？
Did everyone take it?
はい、じゃあ戻りますか。
Okay, shall we go back?
ぜひぜひツイートしてくださいね。
Please tweet it by all means.
行き過ぎた行き過ぎた。
Went too far, went too far.
ハッシュタグよろしく。
Hashtag please.
ではちょっとね、最後の曲に行く前に、一言ずついただこうかなと思いますので...
So, before the last song, I'd like to get a few words from everyone, so...
ビブー、どうだった？
Biboo, how was it?
えーと、めっちゃ楽しかった！
Um, it was so much fun!
イェーイ！
Yeah!
ビブーも...
Biboo too...
えへ... ありがとう。
Hehe... thank you.
"Japanese is very good, すごい" ってコメントいっぱいありました。
There were lots of comments saying 'Japanese is very good, amazing'.
ありがとうございます！日本語、ちょっと難しいです、でも... 楽しかったです！
Thank you! Japanese is a little difficult, but... it was fun!
すごい！めっちゃプラクティスしてくれたね。
Amazing! You practiced a lot, didn't you?
めっちゃプラクティス。
Lots of practice.
あのENのね、ライブ8月にありまして...
Um, the EN live was in August...
そちらのアーカイブが9月25日とかだったかな？もうちょっと見れますので、ぜひそちらも見てください。
The archive for that is until September 25th or something? You can watch it a little longer, so please check it out.
Check it out!
そしてカリ先輩？
And Calli-senpai?
Oh, あたし、あー... もっと歌いたかった。
Oh, I, ah... wanted to sing more.
この夜が続いて欲しかった〜♪
I wanted this night to continue~♪
本当だよ！
Really!
本当に楽しかった。実はあたし、昔、あの... まスタートから、あの、ま、3Dがゲットした時...
It was really fun. Actually, I, a long time ago, um... well from the start, um, well, when I got 3D...
まあ、超久しぶりですね。
Well, it's been a super long time.
ずっとまたやりたかったけど、まあ機会がなくて。
I've wanted to do this again for ages, but there wasn't a chance.
結構収録がね、あの、被るようになったりとかしましたからね。
Our recording schedules started overlapping quite a bit, didn't they?
そうだね。だから本当にありがとうございます。
That's right. So, really, thank you very much.
とても楽しかったです。
It was so much fun.
なんか照れ照れしてる。
She's acting all shy.
めっちゃかっこよかった。
You were so cool.
なんとカリ先輩は今日ね、みこの5周年のライブから駆けつけで。
Calli-senpai actually rushed here straight from Miko's 5th Anniversary Live today.
すごい！
Amazing!
はしごってこと？
A double header?
できないそんなこと。
Normally you can't do that.
はしごライブですね。
Live hopping, isn't it?
あれもチェックしてほしい。
I want you to check that one out too.
ぜひですね、こちらアーカイブもあるのでぜひ。
Please do, the archive is available.
忙しい。
So busy.
忙しいけど楽しいから。
Busy, but it's fun.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you as well.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
そして、ミオ先輩？
And, Mio-senpai?
はい。
Yes.
いやこうやってね、みんなと一緒に歌うっていうことが楽しかったね。
Well, singing together with everyone like this was really fun.
すごいね、あの今日貴重な時間をもらえて本当に嬉しかったです。
It's amazing. I'm really happy to have this precious time today.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank YOU very much.
いや本当ミオ先輩はソロライブ終わったばっかりで。
Mio-senpai literally just finished her solo live.
そっちも大変だったのにも関わらずね、出演してくださって。
Despite being busy with that, you still came to perform.
でもなんか出たいなと思ったんだけど、
But I really wanted to appear,
なんかどうなってるか不安だから、ちょっと曲数は少なくしてもらったんだけど。
but I was worried about how it would go, so I asked for fewer songs.
確かに一曲少ないね。
True, it is one song less.
気遣いいただきありがとうございます。
Thank you for your consideration.
でも出れてよかった。
But I'm glad I could appear.
本当ソロライブも最高だったし、
Your solo live was truly the best,
ね、アーカイブありますんで是非皆さん見てください。
and the archive is up, so everyone please watch it.
Check it out.
そして、AZKi先輩！
And, AZKi-senpai!
はい、いや本当に今日いい時間を、最高の時間を過ごさせていただきました。
Yes! I really had a wonderful, the best time today.
ね、見てくださった方もありがとうございましたっていうのと、
Thank you to everyone who watched, and also...
今回ねこよちゃんが主催してくれてこのライブがありますので、
since Koyo-chan organized this live for us,
こよちゃんありがとうと。
thank you, Koyo-chan.
こちらこそありがとうございます。
Thank you as well.
ビジューさんも素敵な演奏ありがとうございました。
And thank you, Bijou-san, for the lovely performance.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
本当に最高です。
It's truly the best.
素晴らしい。
Wonderful.
またIn Summerですか？
Is it 'In Summer' again?
In Winterあるんですか？
Will there be an 'In Winter'?
やりたいなっていう気持ちを込めてね、
I'm putting in my wish to do it...
あの4回できますね。
We can do it four times, right?
やろうやろう！
Let's do it!
声次第ですよね。
It depends on everyone's voices.
今日のライブの感想とかをね、
Please let us know your thoughts on today's live.
ぜひぜひ教えていただけたらなと思います。
We'd love to hear from you.
ありがとうございました。
Thank you very much.
お願いします。
Please.
そしてAZKi先輩は11月にソロライブが。
And AZKi-senpai has a solo live in November.
はい、あります。
Yes, I do.
はい、よかったら是非見に来ていただけたら嬉しいです。
Yes, I'd be happy if you could come and see it.
めちゃくちゃ楽しみにしております。
I'm looking forward to it so much.
楽しみー！
Can't wait!
ここ立ってます、今。
I'm standing right here now.
配信チケットもありますんでね。
There are streaming tickets too.
是非皆さんご覧ください。
Everyone, please check it out.
よろしくお願いします。
Thank you.
はい、ということでですね、ま、今日はあの...
Yes, so, well, today...
本当この主催をしてみたのは、
The reason I tried organizing this was,
ま、みんなの歌聴きて、みんなと一緒に歌いてみたいな、
I wanted to hear everyone sing, and sing together with everyone,
気持ちもすごくありまして、そしてピアノと一緒に歌いたいっていう、
I really had that feeling, and I wanted to sing with the piano,
気持ちもすごくありまして、やったんですけど、
so I did it, and...
本当に最高の時間でした。
It was truly the best time.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
Thank you!
最後の曲はちょっとね名残惜しいんですけど、
It's a shame, but for the last song...
はい、あのこのまま歌わせていただきたいと思いますよ。
Yes, we'd like to sing it just like this.
皆さん何の曲だと思いますか？
What song do you think it is?
What song do you think we're gonna sing last?
Last song何？
What's the last song?
Guess?
ラストソングをゲスできるのか？
Can you guess the last song?
できるかな？
Can they do it?
SSS?
ああ、SSS。
Ah, SSS.
確かに。
Fair guess.
青春アーカイブ。
Seishun Archive.
あ、それ最初に流れてたか。
Ah, that played at the beginning.
歌うって思うよねって話してましたね。
We were saying they'd probably think we'd sing that.
なんか正解もありそうですけど。
Seems like there might be a correct answer.
ありそう？
Really?
まあ結構割れてますけど、結構夏の歌といえばというこの曲で、
The guesses are pretty split, but we'll close with this song that screams 'summer'.
締めさせていただきたいと思います。
We'd like to close with this.
それでは聞いてください。
Please listen.
secret base 〜君がくれたもの〜
Secret Base ~Kimi ga Kureta Mono~
君と夏の終わり
The end of summer with you,
将来の夢
future dreams,
大きな希望を忘れない
I won't forget our great hopes.
10年後の8月
August, 10 years later,
また出会えるのを信じて
I believe we'll meet again.
最高の
The best
思い出を
memories.
出会いはふっとした瞬間
We met in a sudden moment,
帰り道の交差点で
at the intersection on the way home.
声をかけてくれたね
You called out to me,
「一緒に帰ろう」
'Let's go home together'.
僕は照れくさそうに
I looked shy,
カバンで顔を隠して
hiding my face with my bag.
本当はとてもとても嬉しかったよ
Actually, I was very, very happy.
あぁ 花火が夜空 きれいに咲いて ちょっとセツナク
Ah, fireworks blooming beautifully in the night sky, it's a little bittersweet.
あぁ 風が時間とともに 流れる
Ah, the wind flows along with time.
嬉しくって 楽しくって 冒険もいろいろしたね
We were happy, having fun, and went on various adventures.
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget the end of summer with you, our future dreams, and big hopes.
10年後の8月 また出会えるの 信じて
I believe we can meet again in August, 10 years from now.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでたこと 知ってたよ
I knew that you were screaming "Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile... it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
あぁ 夏休みも あと少しで 終わっちゃうから
Ah, because summer vacation is going to end in just a little while.
あぁ 太陽と月 仲良くして
Ah, sun and moon, please get along.
悲しくって 寂しくって 喧嘩もいろいろしたね
We were sad, lonely, and had various fights too.
二人の 秘密の 基地の中
Inside our secret base.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでたこと 知ってたよ
I knew that you were screaming "Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile... it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
突然の転校で
Because of a sudden transfer...
どうしようもなく
...there was nothing I could do.
手紙書くよ 電話もするよ 忘れないでね 僕のことを
I'll write letters, I'll call too, so don't forget about me.
いつまでも 二人の 基地の中
Forever inside our secret base.
君と夏の終わり ずっと話して
We talked forever at the end of summer with you.
夕日を見てから 星を眺め
We watched the sunset, then gazed at the stars.
君の頬を 流れた涙は ずっと忘れない
I'll never forget the tears that streamed down your cheeks.
君が最後まで 大きく手を振ってくれたこと きっと忘れない
I definitely won't forget how you waved your hand big until the very end.
だからこうして 夢の中で ずっと永遠に…
That's why, like this, inside a dream, forever and ever...
君と夏の終わり 将来の夢 大きな希望 忘れない
I won't forget the end of summer with you, our future dreams, and big hopes.
10年後の8月 また出会えるの 信じて
I believe we can meet again in August, 10 years from now.
君が最後まで 心から 「ありがとう」叫んでたこと 知ってたよ
I knew that you were screaming "Thank you" from your heart until the very end.
涙をこらえて 笑顔でさよなら せつないよね
Holding back tears and saying goodbye with a smile... it's painful, isn't it?
最高の思い出を…
For the best memories...
ありがとう！
Thank you!
Thanks everyone!
Thank you bye bye!
またねー！
See you later!
バイバーイ！
Bye bye!